When you go from synthesis to recommendation, you're going from
“what is the so what of your analysis?” to “what are you actually recommending?”
When you develop the recommendation, you want to think about:
is it appropriate for the organisation?
Is it actionable? How do you actually make this happen?
So let's use an example. Think about the question
of entering a new market with a new product.
The synthesis of your analysis could be:
“We should enter this market with this product, for the following reasons.”
As you develop the recommendation, you think through what needs
to occur — what actions you need to take for that to become true.
Who are the stakeholders you need buy-in from?
What resources may you need to pull together?
And among the different approaches to making it happen,
you want to think about
which is most appropriate, or best, for your organisation.
One tip for making really good recommendations
is to carve out the appropriate time to do it well.
I've often seen people spend a lot of time on the analysis
and get to a pretty good synthesis of the “so what”,
but not carve out enough time to figure out
how to get to the best recommendation —
and how to involve all the different stakeholders, to make sure
the recommendation is as actionable and appropriate as it can be.